♪By red walls and a dry well,
my crown gathers dust and frost♪
♪With a hoe and a patch of wasteland,
I sow the moonlight♪
♪Who says the Cold Palace
holds nothing but tears?♪
♪I choose to fill it with fragrant wine♪
♪Farming in the Cold Palace♪
♪Growing life's simple joys♪
♪Bins full of grain, jars full of wine♪
♪Better than dancing in silks♪
♪Farming in the Cold Palace♪
♪My heart longs for the world beyond♪
♪Tending a courtyard full of life♪
♪Come, share a cup with me♪
(Welcome to Cold Palace Refreshments)
=Farm Busily in the Cold Palace=
(Based on Hongshu.com's novel
I'm Busy Farming in the Cold Palace)
=Episode 18=
Yinshuang, I'm going to bed.
Have Jia and Yi guard the grounds.
Yes.
No one is to come in.
(Welcome back, host.)
(Current farming points: 8,000.)
(You can upgrade your farm to Level 4.)
Didn't you say points could buy items?
I want smallpox treatment methods for
this era.
(Danger
Warning! Warning!)
(This will cost all your farming points)
(and all your stored crops.)
(Confirm exchange?)
Confirm.
(Exchanging...)
(Exchange complete.)
(Transferring smallpox treatment methods
for this era.)
(Scarification
Maintain fluid and mineral balance)
(Natural pH indicator
Isolate patients)
(Silk protein absorbs impurities)
(Disinfect shared areas with quicklime)
(Adjust transfer speed?)
Keep... keep going.
(Honeysuckle detoxification
Powdered borneol and talc)
(Purge heat from the upper body
and drain it downward)
(Draw out rashes and pus
Isolate patients)
You can't die.
Wait for me to get back.
(Powdered borneol and talc)
(Purge heat; draw out rashes and pus)
(Isolate patients; use calamine
Honeysuckle detoxification)
Did it work?
First, I need to extract penicillin
from moldy food.
Culture it by fermentation,
purify with acids and alkalis,
then separate it using animal fat.
Wait.
Where can I get that in this era?
Right!
I think my professor said
fresh pomelo peel yields citric acid
for use in separation.
I planted pomelos!
But it cleared out all my stock.
System!
System, get out here!
You can take everything else,
but give me back my pomelos!
(Exchange rules cannot be changed.)
Wait!
Can I buy them on credit?
I'll pay you back when I grow more!
(Searching...)
(Sorry. No precedent found.)
There's an epidemic out there!
The emperor's about to die!
Donglan is about to fall!
Who'll buy my crops then?
Then how will you get points?
(Agreed.)
(Interest will be charged at 50%.)
Fine, fine, fine!
Give me the pomelos, now!
Hand them over!
(Special Loan Agreement)
You greedy merchant.
(Agreement in effect)
(Cold Palace)
Yinshuang.
Peel the pomelos.
Yes, my lady.
Matron, go to the Cold Palace kitchen
and get moldy rice water and vegetables.
Yes, my lady.
Jia.
Yes?
Bring me a chamber pot.
Yes, my lady.
Yi.
Get some horse manure from the stables.
Right away.
Wait!
Make sure it's fresh!
Hmph.
Finest Hetian jade
conducts and retains heat.
It cost a fortune.
Ji Wujue,
you'd better pay me back.
Mixing pomelo juice with the ferment
creates separate layers.
Human urine is a natural pH indicator.
Silk protein binds impurities.
It worked! It worked!
Brother.
This is all my fault.
If it weren't for me...
If you hadn't
always been such a fool,
incapable of anything great,
I might have thought
you were an enemy assassin.
They say
the dying speak kindly.
Why are your words still so cruel?
Who says we're dying?
Is there a woman you fancy?
Once you're well,
I'll arrange your marriage.
One won't be enough.
I want two.
How is Prince Rui?
Heaven will protect His Highness.
Hear that?
Stop talking
and save your strength.
Brother.
Do you remember
when our eldest brother locked you in
the library?
I stole Father's key
and rushed to the dog hole to save you.
But then
I got stuck,
wailing for the whole palace to hear.
That was so long ago.
Why bring it up?
But
I told you then
that hole
was far too small for you.
But you
still got me out.
They mocked my mother for being a
singer.
You always looked after me.
You always clung to me like glue.
I resented you once, you know.
You learned how to rule,
while I could only learn how to serve.
Why were you born the crown prince,
with an empress for a mother?
But the night she died,
though you were trembling with fear,
you kept vigil all night
in my place.
Because you said
an emperor must not cry.
Who let you in?
If I hadn't come when I did,
he'd have started to stink!
Brother.
My mother
has come for me.
Do you want to die?
Get out!
I can see Father dancing too!
See?
He's already delirious.
Lu Yunluo.
This isn't a chill.
It's smallpox.
I know.
Then why are you here?
Ji Wujue.
Do you trust me?
My lady, the sun is scorching.
Will it really rain tomorrow?
It will if I say it will.
You really didn't lie to me.
Your Majesty, what now?
We wait.
(If this time,)
(we both survive...)
Your Majesty.
If the Emperor truly has the disease,
you mustn't risk your health.
Cao Zhongquan.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I hear His Majesty is unwell.
What did the Medical Office say?
Your Majesty,
they say it's from overwork.
It's merely a chill.
A mere chill
needs Imperial Guards?
So he's guarding against me?
Wujue.
I came especially to see you.
Thank you for your concern, Mother.
I'm quite well.
My child, look at you.
You've had me so worried.
If you're so worried,
why not come inside?
Then I won't disturb your recovery.
Rest well, Your Majesty.
Visiting the sick?
Hmph.
I think
you're just waiting for me to die.
♪By red walls and a dry well,
my crown gathers dust and frost♪
♪With a hoe and a patch of wasteland,
I sow the moonlight♪
♪Who says the Cold Palace
holds nothing but tears?♪
♪I choose to fill it with fragrant wine♪
♪Cool dew, starry nights,
wheat sprouts in my hands♪
♪I shape fields, not painted brows,
and fill them with hope♪
♪Gold and silver bloom from the soil♪
♪I smile as the world storms on♪
♪No finery to rival spring♪
♪All I wish for are waves of green♪
♪Where is beauty found?♪
♪Just lift your eyes and see♪
♪Farming in the Cold Palace♪
♪Growing life's simple joys♪
♪Bins full of grain, jars full of wine♪
♪Better than dancing in silks♪
♪Farming in the Cold Palace♪
♪My heart longs for the world beyond♪
♪Tending a courtyard full of life♪
♪Come, share a cup with me♪